If you would like to find out more about what I do, you can visit my website at www.canineheadstart.com.
So in this short clip, we are going to be talking about what kind of games you can play with your dogs.
An example, one great game you can play with your dog especially a dog that is recovering from some kind of surgery, spade, neutering or injury, is hide and seek.
You are actually going to be playing hide and seek with the object and this would be a dog that can’t move.
You also can obviously be playing with a dog that can be moving.
I’ve got a toy here and the toy is stuffed with some goodies.
I can put the toy on the floor and I can cover it with a pillow and then I ask the dog to go find the toy.
Once the dog gets good at discovering the toy under a particular pillow, you can actually set up a couple of different pillows.
This will keep your dog amused for quite a while.
Another game you can play with dogs is if you teach them names of different toys.
You could call this for example, a ball, Frisbee and let’s see you could call this their bone.
If you use these names when you are playing with your dog repeatedly, the dog will learn the difference between these objects and then you can lay them out on the floor and send your dog after different objects.
That would be called object recognition or distinction.
You can also play fetch.
Teach your dog has to fetch which is a great way to burn off energy in an active dog.
You can play tug of war with dogs.
Always you want to play tug where you are ending the game and you never want to play tug of war with a dog that has dominance issues and you can also play Frisbee with your dog.
This is another great way for your dog to burn off energy and get some exercise.